# MOHAMMAD REZA KARIMI DASTJERDI

Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering. Université Laval 2325 Rue de l'Université, Québec, QC G1V 0A6, Canada Cell: +1 (418) 265 - 5772 • Email: mohammad.karimi-dastjerdi.1@ulaval.ca • Web Page

## Overview

I am a specialist in computer vision and machine learning. My expertise is to develop learning-based solutions for problems at the intersection of computer vision and computer graphics. My skills span over:

• Lighting Estimation

• High Dynamic Range Imaging

· Novel View Synthesis

• Image-based Lighting

· Generative Models

### Education

<b>PhD Candidate of Electrical Engineering</b> , Université Laval, Canada Dissertation: Lighting Estimation and Capturing for Photo-realistic Virtual Object Insertion	Sep. 2019–Present
MSc in Culture Technology, KAIST, South Korea Thesis: Cinemagraph Generation from a Static Image with Generative Adversarial Networks	Sep. 2017–Jul. 2019
BSc in Computer Engineering, K.N.Toosi University of Technology, Iran	Sep. 2011-Sep. 2016

# **Publications**

- S. Borse, K. Bhardwaj, **M. Karimi Dastjerdi**, H. Park, S. Kadambi, S. Shivakumar, P. Mandke, A. Nayak, H. Teague, M. Hayat, F. Porikli. SubZero: Composing Subject, Style, and Action via Zero-Shot Personalization. Under review.
- M. Karimi Dastjerdi, F. Fortier-Chouinard, Y. Hold-Geoffroy, C. Demers, M, Hébert, N. Kalantari, J. Lalonde. PanDORA: Casual HDR Radiance Acquisition for Indoor Scenes. Under review. [Project page]
- J. Giroux, M. Karimi Dastjerdi, Y. Hold-Geoffroy, J. Vazquez-Corral, J. Lalonde. Towards a Perceptual Evaluation Framework for Lighting Estimation. IEEE / CVF Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition Conference (CVPR) 2024. [Project page]
- M. Karimi Dastjerdi, Y. Hold-Geoffroy, J. Eisenmann, J. Lalonde. EverLight: Indoor-Outdoor Editable HDR Lighting Estimation. International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) 2023. [Project page]
- M. Karimi Dastjerdi, Y. Hold-Geoffroy, J. Eisenmann, S. Khodadadeh, J. Lalonde. Guided Co-Modulated GAN for 360° Field of View Extrapolation. IEEE International Conference on 3D Vision (3DV) 2022, Oral presentation. [Project page]
- P. Gera, M. Karimi Dastjerdi, C. Renaud, P. J. Narayanan, J. Lalonde. Casual Indoor HDR Radiance Capture from Omnidirectional Images. The British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC) 2022. Spotlight presentation. [Projet page]

# **Research Experience**

### Research Assistant, Computer Vision and Systems Laboratory, Université Laval

Sep. 2019-Present

- Proposing different methods based on Neural Radiance Fields (NeRF) and 360° cameras to capture HDR radiance of indoor scenes.
- Advised two graduate students and mentored multiple interns in their projects.

## **Interim Engineering Intern, Qualcomm**

Sep. 2024-Dec. 2024

- Working on diffusion models for edge devices with limited resources.

### Research Intern, Adobe

May. 2022-Mar. 2023

- Proposed a lighting estimation method that works for both indoor and outdoor domains seamlessly and produces high dynamic range, high-resolution panoramas ready to use as HDRI in rendering engines.
- Introduced lighting comodulation in GANs, combining the flexibility and intuitiveness of parametric lighting models with the generative power of GANs, resulting in easily editable outputs.
- Adobe is currently integrating the proposed method for the Match Image feature of Adobe Substance 3D Stager.

### Research Scientist Intern, Adobe

May. 2021-Nov. 2021

- Presented an end-to-end trainable pipeline based on GANs specifically tailored to the 360° FOV extrapolation.
- Introduced guided co-modulation mechanism in GANs to edit the content of the generated pixels without any GAN inversion.
- At the time, demonstrated state-of-the-art results both quantitatively and qualitatively.
- It is currently being integrated for face anonymization in Adobe Photoshop and Match Image in Adobe Substance 3D Stager.
- This work is featured at Adobe Max Sneaks 2022 as #ProjectBeyondTheSeen.

### **Patents**

- M. Karimi Dastjerdi, Y. Hold-Geoffroy, S Bi, J. Eisenmann, J. Lalonde, Artificial Intelligence Techniques For Extrapolating HDR Panoramas From LDR Low FOV Images, Worldwide applications, Application no. 18238290 Pending.
- M. Karimi Dastjerdi, Y. Hold-Geoffroy, J. Eisenmann, V. Kim, J. Lalonde, Extrapolating Panoramas from Images using a Generative Model Worldwide applications, Application no. 18055716 Pending.
- J. Noh, H. Lee, B. Kim, G. Kim, J. Lelong, **M. Karimi Dastjerdi**, A. Kim, J. Lee, Image Processing Method and Device Therefor, US patent Patent no. 11893704. February 2024.

# **Honors and Awards**

ICCV Doctoral Consortium (Oct. 2023)

Winner of Otis-Lalonde Scholarship (Mar. 2023)

Bourse en vision artificielle 2e et 3e cycle, Québec, Canada

Presentation Competition: First Place (Apr. 2022), Second Place (Apr. 2021)

Journées de la relève en intelligence et données, Québec, Canada

Machine Vision: Explorer League: First Place (Sep. 2015) Second Place (Nov. 2014) SharifCup Open Robotics Competition, Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

# **Professional Experiences**

Chair, IEEE Young Professionals Affinity Group, IEEE Quebec Section (2021 - 2023)

**Reviewer**, SIGGRAPH ASIA (2024), ECCV (2024), CVPR (2024), IEEE TVCG (2024, 2023), 3DV (2024, 2021), CVPR workshop (2024), ICCV workshop (2021).

Student Committee Member, ICRoM 2014, 2016.

**Technical Committee Member**, The 2<sup>nd</sup> International Students Competition in Robotic, Amirkabir University of Technology, Tehran, Iran. Mar. 2016.

**Technical Committee Member**, The 1<sup>st</sup> KNTU Workshop on Robotics and Embedded Systems, Khazar University, Baku, Azerbaijan. Dec. 2015.

# Computer skills

Programming languages Python, C++, and C

Machine Learning PyTorch, Keras, Tensorflow

Computer Graphics Blender, Maya, Unity3D

## Language

English (Proficient) Persian (Native) Korean (Basic) French (Basic)

# REFERENCES

#### Prof. Jean-François Lalonde

Full Professor

Electrical and Computer Engineering Department

Université Laval, Québec, CA

Email: jflalonde@gel.ulaval.ca

### Dr. Jonathan Eisenmann

Senior Manager - Tech Transfer

Creative Product

Adobe, San Francisco, USA

Email: eisenman@adobe.com

#### **Dr. Yannick Hold-Geoffroy**

Senior Research Scientist,

Adobe Research

Adobe, San Jose, USA

Email: holdgeof@adobe.com

### Prof. Junyong Noh

Full Professor

Graduate School of Culture Technology

KAIST, Daejeon, South Korea

Email: junyongnoh@kaist.ac.kr